Finding Aid for Prentiss Marsh Brown Papers 1902-1973
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Visual Materials
  The Visual Materials series consists of photographs of Brown and his family, also photographs accumulated during his public career. There is also a videotape of a Universal Newsreel film entitled "Price Control Bill Freezes Prices, Wages" and original editorial cartoons from the period when Brown was head of the OPA.
  - Photographs
    (additional photographs on walls of the Prentiss Brown Room at the Bentley Library)
    - Detroit City Hall circa 1870 (Folder Ac)
      (includes copyprints of new city hall building and of ceremony moving into new building)
    - Detroit parade and 250th birthday 1951 (Box 28)
    - Detroit Edison (Box 28)
    - Mackinac Bridge (Box 28)
      (see also photo of Brown, Senator John Kennedy, and G. Mennen Williams at Bridge in 1960)
    - Mackinac Island and Arnold Transit Co (Box 28)
    - Portraits and family: contains photos of Albion College baseball team 1908 and James J. Brown law office 1913 (Box 28)
      (see also oversize folder Ac)
    - St. Ignace: view from hillside of St. Ignace and of St. Ignace Courthouse circa 1900 (Folder Ac)
    - Senator (Box 28)
      (include group photo of Brown as member of the Truman Committee; Brown with John Nance Garner and Arthur Vandenberg, 1940; Brown with Alben Barkley and James Byrnes; and Brown speaking at the dedication of the Blue Water Bridge with Frank Murphy in background 1938)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 28)
  - Videotape
    - "Price Control Bill Freezes Prices, Wages," October 5, 1943, 1 U-matic and VHS copy of film (Box 28)
      (original nitrate film destroyed after copying)
  - Editorial cartoons
    - Cartoons from the Evening Star drawn by C. K. Berryman relating to politics and Brown's work with the O.P.A., 4 items (Folder Ac)
    - Cartoon from the Detroit Free Press drawn by Arthur Poinier relating to the O.P.A., 1 items (Folder Ac)
- Sound Recordings
  Sound Recordings consists of an audiotape of a Detroit Edison function in 1953 and several phonograph records of speeches made by Brown.
  - Audio-tapes (reel-to-reel)
    - Detroit Edison dedication program December 18, 1953, 2 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes (Box 28)
    - Stenorett recordings of interview with Prentiss M. Brown 1967, 6 audiotapes reel-to-reel (Box 28)
      (conducted by J. Fraser Cocks III)
  - Phonorecords
    - Washington Reports on Rationing 1943
      Produced by the Council on Candy as Food in the War Effort under the sponsorship of the National Confectioners Association
      - Guest: Prentiss M. Brown February 14, 1943, 11 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Guests: Claude R. Wickard and Harold B. Rowe February 28, 1943, 2 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Guest: Robert P. Patterson March 7, 1943, 2 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Guest: Paul V. McNutt March 14, 1943, 2 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Guest: Mrs. Phillip M. Crowlie and Harold B. Rowe March 21, 1943, 2 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Guest: Prentiss M. Brown March 28, 1943, 2 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Guest: William L. Batt April 4, 1943, 2 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Report April 11, 1943, 2 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Guest: Roy Hendrickson April 18, 1943, 2 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Guest: Colonel Paul Logan April 25, 1943, 2 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Guest: Joseph Eastman May 2, 1943, 1 phonograph records (Box 29)
    - Other recordings
      - Minute Man Spots, Prentiss Brown on defense savings bonds, 1 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Speech on behalf of the Michigan Democratic Party October 31, 1940, 4 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Interview at Omaha, Nebraska March 18, 1943, 2 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Speech at Kalamazoo, Michigan June 13, 1942, 1 phonograph records (Box 29)
      - Speech at Milwaukee, Wisconsin March 16, 1943, 2 phonograph records (Box 29)
- Microfilmed Materials 1932-1973, 12 rolls
  Materials retained by the family have been copied. This Microfilmed Materials series (1932-1973; 12 rolls) includes diaries kept by Brown from 1942 to 1973. The microfilm was includes scrapbooks, the originals of which are described in the Scrapbooks and Clippings series. One of the microfilm reels consists of Brown material located in the Franklin Roosevelt Library in Hyde Park, New York.
  - Diaries
    - 1942-July 2, 1944 (Reel 1)
    - July 2, 1944-1951 (Reel 2)
    - 1952-December 1958 (Reel 3)
    - December 1958-1962 (Reel 4)
    - 1963-1966 (Reel 5)
    - 1967-1970 (Reel 6)
    - 1970-1973 (Reel 7)
  - Appointment book
    - 1960-1973 (Reel 7)
  - Scrapbooks
    - March 9, 1932-April 1937 (Reel 8)
    - April 1937-1940 (Reel 9)
    - 1941-1942 (Reel 10)
    - 1945-1954 (Reel 11)
  - Correspondence
    - 1937-1942 (Reel 12)
      (originals in the Roosevelt Library, Hyde Park, New York)
Selective index to correspondents
Abbott, Horatio J. (Harold Johnson), 1876-
Jan. 1934, Nov. 1934, July 1935, Mar. 1936, Apr. 1936
Andrews, Roger Mercein, 1874-1943
(Pres.: Mackinac Island St. Park Comm.)
Jan. 1934, Apr. 1934, Feb. 1935, Apr. 1935, Sept. 1935, Oct. 1935, Dec. 1935, Jan. 1936, Mar. 1936, Apr. 1936, Sept. 1937
Averill, George R 1893-1971.
1942 [In folder 4-1]
Avery, Sewell
(Montgomery Ward Executive)
Oct. 5, 1942, Oct. 28, 1942, Dec. 3, 1942, Dec. 12, 1942
Barkley, Alben William, 1877-1956.
July 1937, Sept. 1938
Bell, Jack L., 1904
(Associated Press, Senate Gallery)
Dec. 24, 1942, Jan. 5, 1943
Bennett, Harry Herbert, 1892
Apr. 21, 1942, May 11, 1942
Byrnes, James Francis, 1879-
May 1, 1943
Cady, Claude Ernest, 1878-1953.
(6th District, U.S. Congress)
May 1935
Cleary, Gerald J.
(Chairman - Delta County. Democratic Comm.)
Mar. 1933, May 1933, May 1934, June 1934, Nov. 1936, Aug. 1937, Sept. 1937, Feb. 23, 1939 in folder 3-46, Mar. 11, 1939 in folder 3-47
Comstock, William Alfred, 1877-1949.
Sept. 17, 1940 [In folder 3-51]
Couzens, Frank, 1902-1950.
Nov. 1936, Feb. 1938
Couzens, James Joseph, 1872-1936.
Jan. 1936
Debo, Alfred
May 1933, May 1934, June 1934, Jan. 1935
DeFoe, Murl Holcomb, 1879-
Mar. 1937, Apr. 1937, May 1937
Diggs, Charles Coles, 1922-
Sept. 11, 1940 in folder 3-51
Dingell, John David, 1894-1955.
(15th District, U.S. Congress)
Nov. 3, 1937, Nov. 8, 1937
Downey, Sheridan, 1884-1961
(Democratic candidate for the U.S. Senate from California)
Oct. 1938 [In folder 3-42]
Eccles, Marriner Stoddard, 1890-
(Chairman, Federal Reserve System)
Dec. 19, 1942
Farley, James Aloysius, 1888-
June 1934, Nov. 1937, Dec. 1937, Mar. 1938, Aug. 1938, Aug. 30, 1940
Fead, Louis H 1877-1943.
(Michigan Supreme Court)
Mar. 1933, June 1933, Mar. 1934, May 1934, Nov. 1934, July 1937
Fenlon, Edward H.
(State Representative - St. Ignace/Law Partner)
May 1933, June 1933, Feb. 1934, Mar. 1934, May 1934
Fitzgerald, Frank Dwight, 1885-1939.
Oct. 1935, Nov. 1935
Garner, John Nance, 1868-1967.
Oct. 1938 in folder 3-42
Gomon, Josephine
May 1937
Green, Fred Warren, 1872-1936.
Dec. 1935
Guffey, Joseph F 1870-1959. (U.S. Senator, Pennsylvania)
Dec. 22, 1942
Hatch, Carl A 11889-1963.
Feb. 16, 1942
Hatfield, Malcolm Keith, 1900-1961.
(Judge - Probate and Juvenile Courts, St. Joseph)
June 28, 1938, Feb. 8, 1939 (P), Apr. 7, 1939 [In folder 3-47]
Henderson, Leon, 1895-
(Administrator - OPA)
Sept. 22, 1942, Dec. 12, 1942
Hook, Frank Eugene, 1893
Aug. 22, 1943
Hoover, John Edgar, 1895-1972
Mar. 23, 1942
Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955.
Mar. 1933, Apr. 1933, Sept. 1939, Oct. 11, 1939, Apr. 5, 1940
Hurja, Emil Edward, 1892
June 1934, Aug. 1935
Jackson, Robert Houghwout, 1892-1954.
(U.S. Attorney General)
May 25, 1940
James, William Francis, 1873-1945.
Jan. 1934, Feb. 1934
Jones, Jesse Holman, 1874-1956.
(Chairman - RFC)
June 20, 1936 (P)
Kennedy, George Donald, 1909
Apr. 1935, Feb. 25, 1935 (P)
Kimmerle, Charles H 1860-
Feb. 1936
Kresge, Sebastian Spering, 1867-1966.
Sept. 20, 1945
Lederle, Arthur F, 1887-
(U.S. District Judge)
Feb. 1937, Nov. 1937, May 31, 1940, Aug. 7, 1940
Lehr, John Camillus, 1878-1958.
(U.S. Congress - 2nd District, Michigan)
Feb. 1935, Mar. 1935, Apr. 1935, Aug. 1935, Dec. 1935, June 1936
Luecke, John, 1889-1952
(State Senator -Escanaba)
Apr. 1936, May 1936, June 1936, May 1940
McAllister, Thomas Francis, 1896-
(U.S. Supreme Court)
1938?, Nov. 1938, 1941? Nov. 4, 1941, July 29, 1943, Apr. 20, 1939 in folder 3-47
McKay, Frank Donald, 1883-1965.
Dec. 1937
Mershon, William Butts, 1856-1943.
May 1934
Morgenthau, Henry, 1856-1946.
Oct. 10, 1942
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.
Dec. 4, 1934, Jan. 7, 1935, July 30, 1935, Sept. 23, 1935, Oct. 2, 1935, Nov. 2, 1935, Dec. 19, 1936, Feb. 10, 1937, May 20, 1937, Aug. 1937
Jan. 28, 1938, Feb. 4, 1938, Apr. 28, 1938, Apr. 1938, May 10, 1938, May 16, 1938, Nov. 7, 1938, Dec. 21, 1938, Jan. 12, 1939, Jan. 14, 1939, Jan. 19, 1939, Feb. 1939, Mar. 1939, Feb. 27
1940, June 10, 1942, Jan. 11, 1943; Feb. 13, 1939 letter from Frank Picard in folder 3-46; Apr. 7, 1939 Report on politics from M. Hatfield in folder 3-47
Musselwhite, Harry Webster, 1868-1955.
(U.S. Congress, 9th District)
Aug. 1934, Sept. 1934, Oct. 1934, Nov. 1934, Dec. 1934, Jan. 1935
Norris, George William, 1861-1944.
Nov. 27, 1942
Osborn, Chase Salmon, 1860-1949.
Nov. 1934, July 1936, Aug. 1936, Nov. 1936, Dec. 1936, Jan. 1937, Feb. 1937, Mar. 1937, May 1937, Aug. 1937, Sept. 1937, Aug. 1938, Jan. 1939, Oct. 1939
Jan. 1940, Mar. 1940, June 12, 1940, Aug. 1940, Dec. 1940, Apr. 1941, Dec. 5, 1942, Mar. 11, 1943, Apr. 8, 1943 (Brown for Pres.), May 21, 1943, Jan. 26, 1945, Jan. 28, 1946, Apr. 17, 1942 in folder 4-14, May 1942 in folder 4-15
Osborn, Stella (Brunt), 1894-
Dec. 5, 1945
Picard,Frank A., 1889-1963.
Feb. 1936, Dec. 1937, Jan. 1940, Feb. 8, 1939 13-461
Reichert, Rudolph Edward, 1887-1965.
Nov. 1934
Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Pres. U.S., 1882-1945.
Jan. 7, 1942, Oct. 3, 1942, Oct. 7, 1942, Nov. 7, 1942, Nov. 12, 1942, Dec. 7, 1942, Dec. 21, 1942, Dec. 17, 1942, May 29, 1936 in folder 3-39, 2
undated drafts of letters to FDR in folder 1-5, undated letter in folder 3-48, Oct. 28, 1940 in folder 3-52, Oct. 31, 1940 in folder 3-52, Oct. 29, 1940 in folder 3-52, Nov. 4, 1940 in folder 3-53, Nov. 7, 1940 in folder 3-53
Shields, Edmund Claude, 1871-1947.
(Lansing lawyer and politician)
May 1933, Nov. 1934, Mar. 1936, Dec. 1936, 1937?, Jan. 1937, Feb. 1937, Mar. 1937, May 1937, Aug. 1937, July 23, 1940, Oct. 20, 1941, Apr. 8, 1942, May 5, 1943, Oct. 1943, Feb. 20, 1934 (P), Feb. 13, 1935 (P), Jan.-Feb. 1939 in folder 3-46, Mar. 1939 in folder 3-47, June 1940 in folder 3-50
Smith, Gerald Lyman Kenneth, 1898-
1942 in folder 4-4, 1942 in folder 4-5
Smith, Shirley Wheeler, 1875-1959.
Nov. 14, 1942
Spence, Brent, 1874-1967.
(U.S. Congress, 5th District, Kentucky)
Sept. 26, 1934, Nov. 1935, Dec. 1935
Stack, John K., 1884-1935.
(Michigan Auditor General)
Mar. 1933, Apr. 1933
Starr, Raymond Wesley, 1888-1968.
Dec. 1936
Steagall, Henry Bascom, 1873-1943.
(U.S. Congress, Alabama)
Oct. 1934
Toms, Robert M (Judge)
Feb. 1939
Treanor, Arthur R.
(Booth Newspapers)
Dec. 31, 1942
Truman, Harry S1884-1972.
Mar. 29, 1948 in folder 14-31, Nov. 8, 1940 in folder 3-53
Vandenberg, Arthur Hendrick, 1884-1951.
Aug. 17, 1939, Aug 26, 1943, Nov. 14, 1940 in folder 3-53
Van Wagoner, Murray Delos, 1898-
Nov. 1935, Mar. 1940
Wagner, Robert Ferdinand, 1877-1953
Mar. 27, 1941
Welsh, George Wilson, 1883-1974.
(Mayor, Grand Rapids)
Apr. 12, 1938, Mar. 11, 1942, Apr. 3, 1942
White, Walter Francis, 1893-1955.
Oct. 14, 1942 (re. Brown's record on black issues)
Woodfill, W S
Feb. 1933, Mar. 1933, July 23, 1943, Apr. 22, 1951